https://cpaws-sask.org/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy - CPAWS Saskatchewan
About
Who Are We?
A. PIPEDA
The Canadian Parks and Wilderness Society (CPAWS) is committed to respecting the privacy of our members, their families, and our employees by adhering to the privacy principles set forth in the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA). Those principles are:
1. Accountability
CPAWS is responsible for personal information under its control. The Executive Director is accountable to the National Trustees for compliance with this statement. The Development Coordinator is the Chief Privacy Officer, and is responsible for the management of the statement including the guiding principles.
2. Identifying purposes
CPAWS, at or before the time personal information is collected, will identify the purpose for which personal information is collected. The primary purposes are fundraising, statistics and meeting legal and regulatory requirements. Specifically, this includes processing gifts, issuing receipts, mailing of newsletters, direct mail, telemarketing, trading names with like-minded organizations, sending invitations to events, informing donors about new products or services, and maintaining a list of members as required by the Canada Corporations Act. In addition, CPAWS shares personal information with our regional chapters for the same purposes. When personal information that has been collected is to be used for a purpose not previously identified, the new purpose will be identified prior to use. Unless law requires the new purpose, the consent of the individual is required before information can be used for that purpose.
3. Consent
All donors have the ability to consent to the uses of their personal information. CPAWS makes a reasonable effort to ensure that individuals are advised of the purposes for which information will be used. CPAWS will assume consent is granted unless a member indicates otherwise. Individuals may withdraw consent in many ways.
For example:
By filling out and returning the member services survey sent out with tax receipts
By calling us at (800) 333-9453
By sending an email to info@cpaws.org
In writing An individual may withdraw consent at any time.
4. Limiting Collection
CPAWS will limit its collection of personal information to the purposes outlined in Principle 2 above. If it is necessary to use the personal information collected for a purpose not identified when the information was collected, consent for the new use will be obtained from the donor.
5. Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention of Personal Information
Personal information will not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual, or as required by law Personal information will be retained by CPAWS for whatever periods are required by legislation governing our operation and/or the information provided, plus three years, after which time (unless consent is given to keep information for a longer period) the information will be destroyed in a secure manner. Personal information regarding donors of planned gifts will be kept until the death of the donor, plus ten years.
6. Accuracy
Personal information will be as accurate, complete, and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used.
7. Safeguards
CPAWS has security safeguards in place that protect personal information against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, or modification. CPAWS will protect personal information regardless of the format in which it is held. Methods of protection include:
Physical measures, for example, locked filing cabinets and restricted access to offices;
Organizational measures, for example, limiting access on a "need-to-know" basis, and
Technological measures, for example, the use of passwords.
CPAWS makes its employees aware of the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of personal information.
8. Openness
This statement and the processes and procedures for obtaining access to personal information will be available to any individual through our web site, and/or on request. If any individual has a question regarding personal information, it may be directed to the Chief Privacy Officer.
9. Individual Access
On request, an individual will be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of their personal information, and will be given access to that information. An individual may challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information, and have it corrected or amended as appropriate. An individual will be required to provide sufficient information to permit CPAWS to provide an account of the existence, use, and disclosure of personal information. CPAWS will respond to an individual's request within a reasonable time and at minimal or no cost to the individual.
10. Challenging Compliance
Individuals may challenge CPAWS' compliance with this statement by contacting the Chief Privacy Officer.
B. CPAWS WEBSITE
Donations and purchases made through the CPAWS website are processed by Convio Luminate Online. The information gathered through Convio is collected for the CPAWS database, and may be used for future communications with CPAWS members consistent with the purposes outlined above. Please visit Convio for additional information on their privacy and security practices.
CPAWS does not maintain a secure web interface at any other point on this site. CPAWS does not collect or distribute the email addresses of visitors to our web page. CPAWS does collect aggregate information on which pages visitors access or visit, and information volunteered by the visitor, such as survey information and/or site registrations. The information we collect is used to improve the content of our Web page, and is not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes. With respect to security,
CPAWS always uses industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving consumer data exchanged with our site. We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.
C. CONTACTING CPAWS
CPAWS National Office
600-100 Gloucester Street
Ottawa, ON K2P 0A4
Tel: (613) 569-7226
Toll Free: 1-800-333-WILD (9453)
To receive news and updates from CPAWS, including opportunities to get involved, join our action list below.
Saskatchewan Chapter@ The Two Twenty202- 220 20th St,Saskatoon, SKS7M 0W9
The CPAWS Saskatchewan offices are located on Treaty 6 Territory and the traditional Homeland of the Métis.
Who Are We?
